Brett Stoudt

Software Engineer

941-718-3121

www.linkedin.com/in/Brett-Stoudt/

www.github.com/BStoudt01

BStoudt01@Gmail.com

SUMMARY

I love to adventure into new territories, and discover new places and in that respect I've been testing the waters of the tech industry my entire life.

From troubleshooting desktops with my dad to apprenticing with IT staff in middle school my childhood was filled with computers. In the following years I learning digital design and programming basics in high school and those experiences gave me the understanding to build a website using wordpress and design operation tools for the brewery industry. The drive to fulfill my curiosity is only one of the reasons I pursued my career in software development.

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack

Web Developer Certificate

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY

 Bachelors Degree in Environmental Studies

MANATEE COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Associate of Arts

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER BOOTCAP

Nashville Software School 2020

Experiences:

- Agile Scrum Methodology
- Remote Team Building

Tech:

- HTML and CSS
- JavaScript and React
- Full CRUD Operations
- GitHub, Postman, JSON-Server
- CSharp
- SQL

Group Projects

NUTSHELL - ASKING FOR ROSES

github.com/bstoudt01/nutshell-asking-for-roses

Nutshell is a social media platform that included friends, articles, events, tasks and a message board for the users to experience.

My contributions included:

- Full CRUD for the article section,
- Handling Session Storage

HEIST - THE BURGLIN BURATTAS

github.com/bstoudt01./burglin-burattas

Heist is a simulator for making the right choice when robbing a store. This project was a great mob coding experience in our group of 4 i was able to sudo code the entire game.

- The Gang Leader can create a gang with stats including courage and skill for each thug
- Then Choose the place you plan to rob and how difficult a it is to stick up
- Run through a few scenarios and see how it plays out, especially when you consider the luck factor.

PROJECTS

BREWMORE

github.com/bstoudt01/BrewMore

BrewMore offers Breweries a profitable outlook on ordering materials and storage of brand recipes by reducing time required to order ingredients and increasing the accuracy of ingredients needed to complete the job.

- Brewers can create a recipe card for each brand of beer they would like to keep on-line
- The brewer can then add instances of each recipe to an ordering page,
- The ordering page totals the grain required for all potential brews.
- The grain totals are listed by pounds and by the bag, and is ready to be sent to the brewers grain supplier.
- BrewMore is my NSS Front-End Capstone designed using React Bootstrap,

BACK END CAPSTONE

github.com/bstoudt01/BrewMore

BrewMore offers Breweries a profitable outlook on ordering materials and storage of brand recipes by reducing time required to order ingredients and increasing the accuracy of ingredients needed to complete the job.

- Brewers can create a recipe card for each brand of beer they would like to keep on-line
- The brewer can then add instances of each recipe to an ordering page,
- The ordering page totals the grain required for all potential brews.
- The grain totals are listed by pounds and by the bag, and is ready to be sent to the brewers grain supplier.
- BrewMore is my NSS Front-End Capstone designed using React Bootstrap,

WORK EXPERIENCE

Brett Stoudt

CLUB SERVICES MANAGER THE RITZ-CARLTON CLUB, ST. THOMAS, VI

Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

- Provided an elevated experience for all members and their guests by ensuring they were escorted through the entire check-in/out process by name.
- Assisted employees in understanding guests' ever-changing needs and expectations, and exceeding them such
 as stocking pre-ordered groceries in a luxury fashion.
- Lead, motivate and challenge multiple guest facing departments to meet property goals by conducting daily line-ups with entire front of house department to discuss potential opportunities and provide focus for the day.
- Created LSOPs for the bell services, member storage, and property greeter roles that are inline with The Ritz-Carlton Standards to provide my Ladies and Gentlemen with the knowledge they deserved.

CELLARMAN & BREWER

ROCK CITY BREWING, ST. THOMAS, VI

JANUARY 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

- Coordinated with coworkers and owners to meet production goals by Implementing online scheduling and production tracking systems, utilizing Google.
- Increased the performance and efficiency of keg washing equipment, redesigning flow path to include multiple kegs, doubling kegs cleaned per a shift from 30 to 60.
- Introduced new production aids & techniques such as introducing a clarity agent that is vegan friendly.
- Designed and installed more efficient draft systems at multiple locations, cutting beer loss in half.
- Designed and installed CO2 distribution system for the production site, allowing CO2 cylinders to be stored and accessed in a safer manner.
- Designed and installed a mobile draft system in a smart car for events & parties.

MOUNTAIN SUN PUB & BREWERY - BOULDER/DENVER, CO

SEPTEMBER 2011 - DECEMBER 2018

DIRECTOR OF WAREHOUSE & LOGISTICS

NOVEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2018

- Worked side by side with owners, management and production site leads to solve logistical challenges.
- Created, implemented and maintained programs for multiple operation areas including production timeline, inventory management, and distribution to help drive automation of business operations in an effort to provide the best tasting product to our customers.
- Created and maintained multiple S.O.P.'s for distribution and equipment maintenance to properly outline department expectations and provide protection for company assets.
- Created and executed OSHA certified safety program, primarily focusing on HAZCOM to ensure my coworkers had the knowledge and equipment to keep them safe on the job.
- Created and maintained forklift training and maintenance programs at multiple locations as a certified instructor of lift truck operators.
- Monitored multiple projects and locations for quality control and legal compliance.
- Worked with multiple contractors to maintain and repair equipment at multiple locations
- Key holder for multiple locations
- Credit card and net purchasing power through multiple vendors

WAREHOUSE MANAGER

NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2014

CELLARMAN & DELIVERY DRIVER

SEPTERMBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2012